MY RESUME

## **Profile**

### JOSE FRANCO OLEA VALLEJO

I'm a professional with work experience in software development (Front-End and Back-End), Microsoft Azure cloud services administration and implementation of architecture designs in the cloud to provide solutions to new and current needs, I also have Azure DevOps management experience creating and managing projects and pipelines for continuous integration (CI) and continuous deployment (CD) both in Azure and On-Premise infrastructure.

- # +52 55 2084 6860
- 📧 franco8802@gmail.com

## Languages

SPANISH

Native

ENGLISH

Advanced

### **Education**

 BACHELOR OF "MATEMÁTICAS APLICADAS Y COMPUTACIÓN" (GRADUATED ONLY)

Aug 2012 - Nov 2016

FES Acatlán, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

Groups & activities:

- Algorithmics and Competitive Programming Group
- Videogames Development Group

### Awards & leadership:

- 27th Place in ACM ICPC Mexico Occident & Pacific Programming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico Occident & Pacific Programming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico & Central America Contest, SEDE ESCOM IPN, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Mexico & Central America Programming Contest, SEDE ITSM Querétaro, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC Finals in Mexico CitiesProgramming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Honorable Mention in ACM ICPC JaliscoProgramming Contest, coordinated by ITESO University, 2013
- Recognition by the Government of the State of Mexico for being an Excellence Student and having the best grade in my class, 2012
- Constancy by Academia Mexicana de Lógica, A.C. & Universidad Autónoma de Nayarit for having competed in the final stage of the IX InternationalOlympiad in Logic, 2012

# **Certifications**

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT EXPERT



MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: DEVOPS ENGINEER EXPERT



• MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE DEVELOPER ASSOCIATE



MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE ADMINISTRATOR ASSOCIATE



 DIPLOMAED IN VIDEOGAMES DEVELOPMENT AND INTERACTIVE & 3D MULTIMEDIA APPLICATIONS

Dec 2015 - May 2016

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

# **Professional Experience**

## LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep 2021 - Present

Thomson Reuters

- Tech Lead in the design, development, and maintenance of a product called Contract Express
- Lead the local (Mexico) development team on maintaining and implementing new features for our product.
- Lead the tech design and architecture of new features, like an Al Chat Assistant using RAG model, and a new Ul design implementation in the core of the Ul system.
- Develop and lead new system requirments, designs and bug fixes.
- Implementation of new Github PR templates to standardize Pull Requests information and make code-reviews easier.
- Encouraged the team to develop and grow their technical skills.
- Coach and mentor teammates on technical and soft skills, helping them to improve their performance.
- Took most of the responsibilities of the Scrum Master after he left the team, for more than a year, leading scrum daily ceremonies, improving ADO tasks planning and implementing sprint retrospectives.
- Implemented dashboards to measure team performance and a new dashboard on PowerBI to measure number of opened/solved bugs in ADO which was taken as an example for other teams to have similar dashboards with the same technology.
- Helped on DevOps tasks, creating and modifying ADO build and release pipelines, giving tips, analyzing and helping on modifying the infrastructure of Dev/Prod environments.
- Helped Service team solving issues reported by clients, analyzing and solving the problems, and sometimes having calls with clients to understand and give solutions to their issues.
- Helped Service team on analyzing and creating solutions for Azure infrastructure modification and performance improvements.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

May 2018 - Aug 2021

Comisión Reguladora de Energía

- Tech Lead in the design, development, and maintenance of web services and systems
- Lead development teams (up-to 30 members) for differente projects and requirements.
- Lead the design and architecture of new systems.
- Develop and lead new systems requirments and bug fixes.
- Creation of NuGet packages for custom and generic functions, classes and interfaces.
- Azure administrator
- Implementation of a new architecture for the Azure infrastructure of the institution with geo-redundancy and communication with On-Premise site.
- Creation and management of laaS, PaaS, communication, data and analytics services.
- Cost & budget management and projection based on current and future needs and requirements.
- Infrastructure monitoring with azure alerts and dashboards.
- Azure DevOps administrator
  - Managing and implementing Git Branching strategies and policies,
    Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery pipelines.
- Managing and installing agent pools and deployment pools on Azure and On-Prem Windows servers for Azure Pipelines.
- Migrating TFVC Repositories to Git
- Planning and tracking activities for projects creating sprints and using boards, creating custom Scrum processes according to the needs.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ASSISTANT MANAGER

Dec 2016 - Apr 2018

Comisión Reguladora de Energía

- Manage Azure DevOps repositories and prjects.
- Development and maintenance of web systems and REST APIs with .Net Framework 4.5+ and jQuery.
- Technical problems resolution.
- Continuous improvements of web systems.
- jQuery plugins creation.
- Plugins creation and code refactoring to improve code performance and quality.

# WEB DEVELOPER

Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

Lagash

- Development and maintenance of web systems and REST APIs with .Net Framework 4.5+ and jQuery.
- Technical problems resolution.
- Continuous improvements of web systems.
- jQuery plugins creation.
- Plugins creation and code refactoring to improve quality and code performance.